-你有听说过加州凡奈斯漫展吗  -有啊
- Hey, have you ever heard of the Van Nuys Comic-Con? - Yeah.
就是个破烂小展览  卖卖收藏物
It's a dinky little convention where they sell collectibles
请一些不知名惨兮兮的小咖出场  怎么了
and get sad D-list celebrities to appear. Why?
我被邀请去办签名会
I got asked to sign autographs there.
太屌啦
That's awesome!
是因为《杀人恶猿》吗
Is this for Serial Ape-ist?
可能是因为这部猴子电影  也可能是因为我拍的痔疮广告
Well, it could be for the monkey movie. It could be my hemorrhoid commercial.
反正可能性只有这俩
The list does not go on.
-什么时候  -这不重要  我才不去
- When is it? - It doesn't matter. I'm not doing it.
-为什么  为啥不去  -你刚才自己说了  很惨啊
- What? Why not?  -You just said yourself, it's sad.
但没有到可悲啊  我的底线就是不可悲则可行
Yeah, but it's not pathetic. That's where I draw the line.
-去嘛  肯定有意思  -我也不知道了
-Come on! We'll have fun.  -I don't know.
会有各种宅男对你摇尾乞怜啊
You'll have nerds fawning all over you.
如果你不喜欢这感觉  那我们的婚姻要出大事了
If you don't love that, this marriage is in trouble.
好吧  去见见粉丝  顺便赚点外快也不错
I guess it wouldn't hurt to meet some fans and make a little extra money.
对啊
Yeah.
哇哦
Wow!
大导演乔治·卢卡斯的皮肤科医生也会来
An appearance by George Lucas's dermatologist.
-他的签名我也要了  -好好好
- Oh, I want that autograph. - Oh, yeah.
第十季  第六集
我们现在开始同居了  是不是能考虑试试邀请客人来玩
You know, with us living together, maybe we could think about having people over.
我们整天有人来访啊
We have people over all the time.
有维修工  还有披萨外送员...
We have the maintenance people, the pizza delivery man...
还有那个觉得有必要来关心我最近有没有什么"鸟"事的快递员
...that UPS driver who feels the need to ask how parts of me are hanging.
你知道我说的是什么意思
You know what I meant.
好吧  行
All right, fine.
那就假设我们要宴请朋友
Let's say that we were to entertain people.
你打算举办哪种聚会呢
What type of gathering did you have in mind?
吃饭的话  午餐会  早午餐会  还是晚餐会呢  下午茶的话  是正式的吗
Huh? A meal? Lunch? Brunch? Dinner? Afternoon tea? A formal tea? Hmm?
还是是个派对呢  如果是  那请问是哪种派对
Is it a party? And if so, what kind of party?
是鸡尾酒派对  直销产品派对
A cocktail party? A Tupperware party?
对了  是惊喜派对吗
Ooh, yeah-- is it a surprise party?
我希望不是《西海岸派对》啊
Oh, I hope it's not a West Coast party,
因为根据电台里这首歌的歌词  "西海岸派对永不停歇"啊
'cause according to the man on the radio,a West Coast party don't stop.
对不起  我不应该提起这事
I'm sorry I mentioned it.
不用道歉  你心中燃起希望之火  我一桶冷水把它浇熄
Oh, don't be. You get your hopes up,I knock them down.
这就叫合作无间
That's called teamwork.
踢了  孩子真的踢了一下
That's a kick.That's an actual kick.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我感觉到踢了一下
I felt a kick.
里面有一个宝宝呢
There's a baby in there.
对哦  原来我把宝宝放这里了
Oh, yeah, that's where I put it.
我的意思是  我知道你怀孕了
No, I mean, I know you're pregnant.
只是...我从来没把怀孕
I just...never connected the idea of pregnancy
跟你要生孩子这件事联想到一起
and you actually having a baby.
你去的是哪家麻省理工来着
Which MIT did you go to?
天啊  我们这房子还没准备好迎接宝宝啊
Oh, God, we are not ready to have an infant in this house!
没有婴儿床  也没有尿布
We don't have a crib, we don't have diapers.
也还没弄婴儿保护措施
We're not baby-proofed.
任何人都可以走进家里  掀开没锁上的马桶盖
Anyone can just walk in off the street and lift our toilet lids!
华仔  我们还有时间搞那些东西
Howie, we have time to do all that stuff.
真的有吗  看看你
Do we? Look at you.
就像电影里被推去榨汁的小胖子一样圆
Willy Wonka would roll you to the juicing room.
下一个踢你的人会是老娘  晚安
The next person kicking you will be me.Good night.
我们这里是好的学区...
Are we even in a good school...?
警告过你了  我言出必行
I warned you, and I did it.
这是什么
What's all this?
你办签名会需要的一切东西
Oh, everything we need for your autograph session--
大头照  马克笔
head shots, markers.
等等 莱纳德  你对这事很上心是好事
Okay. Leonard, it's sweet you're excited about this,
但哪怕是有一个人想要我的签名  都能算奇迹
but it'll be a miracle if one person asks for my autograph.
你在开玩笑吧  我有一次花20块去讨西奥·杀死勒的签名呢
Are you kidding? I once paid $20 for Theo Sassler's signature.
他是谁
Who's that?
我也不认识  我只是觉得他名字炫  西奥·杀死勒
Oh, I don't even know. I just liked his name. Theo Sassler!
你看这个  我还弄了一个换零钱机
Oh, and look at this. I even got a change maker.
你要换多少零钱  小姑娘
How much change you want, little lady?
我想要换[掉]的东西多了
Oh, there's so much I want to change.
如果是想要一块钱换硬币  你就来得巧了
Yeah, well, if it's a dollar, you're in luck.
这是怎么一回事
What's going on here?
你表示出了对邀请客人有兴趣
You expressed an interest in having people over,
我觉得我太快驳回你的提议了
and I feel I dismissed it too quickly.
所以我决定亲自着手此事  筹办了一场早午餐会
So, I took matters into my own hands, and I arranged a brunch.
这真是太好了  有谁会来
Well, that's so nice. Who's coming?
斯图尔特  地质学实验室的伯特
Oh, uh, Stuart, Bert from the geology lab,
楼下的佩特雷斯库太太
and Mrs. Petrescu from downstairs.
你是说住二楼的罗马尼亚女士吗
You mean the Romanian lady on the second floor?
是的  说来也好笑
Yes. Oh, fun story:
她从小是跟十个兄弟姐妹一起长大
she grew up with ten siblings.
或是跟企鹅一起长大  她的英语太烂了
Or possibly penguins. Her English is atrocious.
客人的组合好奇怪啊
That's an odd mix of people.
我们第一次邀请客人来家里
Well, for our first time hosting,
我认为先做个试验是明智之举
I thought it would be wise to conduct a trial run.
就像当年我为了万圣节鬼屋练胆
You know, like how I practiced for that Halloween haunted house
于是我去了公车站的厕所
by going into the bathroom at the bus station.
你后来压根没进那间鬼屋
You never went into that haunted house.
那是因为你没看见我在公车站受到什么惊吓
You never saw what jumped out at me at the bus station.
谢谢你  谢尔顿  这真是个有趣的惊喜
Well, thank you, Sheldon. This is a fun surprise.
真正的惊喜是
Well, the real surprise is how surprised
你知道我擅长给人惊喜后有多惊喜
you are that I'm great at surprises.
那根本不算惊喜
Well, that's not a surprise at all.
如果我本来就知道你擅长给人惊喜
I mean, if I knew you were good at surprises,
那我就会预计到有这个惊喜  然后就不会被你"惊喜到"
I would have expected the surprise,and therefore not have been surprised.
可事实上是  我之前不知道  所以我"惊喜"的样子  你根本不该觉得惊喜
But as it is, I didn't know, and therefore my surprise should be unsurprising.
不许用言语挑逗人家  客人随时会到
Don't get me all randy. Guests are on the way.
-回来啦  -你们去哪儿了
-Hi.  -Hey, where you been?
我们去给宝宝买了点东西
Oh, we went and did a little shopping for the baby.
你等着瞧我们选的婴儿床吧
Wait till you see the crib we found.
你买婴儿床不用问过我吗
You bought a crib without me?
-你肯定会喜欢的  -对啊
- You're gonna love it. - Yeah.
它是市场上评价最好的一款  要我就不会说那是婴儿床
It's the highest rated one on the market. I wouldn't even call it a crib.
我会称其为"宝宝的孤独城堡"
I'd call it a Fortress of Solitude for babies.
听起来就是贵货啊
Sounds expensive.
好吧  我可能有点太舍得了
Okay, well, I may have gone a bit overboard,
可安全是无价之宝啊
but you can't put a price on safety.
但如果非要给个价  那会比你想象中多很多个0
Though if you did, it's more zeroes than you're expecting.
但那是市面上最安全的婴儿床
But it's the safest crib you can buy.
-而且如果你不喜欢  我们可以退掉啊  -好吧
-And if you don't like it, we can return it.  - Fine.
它在我们的新面包车里呢  中午吃什么呀
In our new minivan. Hey, what's for lunch?
你还买了一辆面包车吗
You bought a minivan?!
那是为了宝宝啊  而且我又没买
It's for the baby, and I didn't buy it.
卖车那人借给我试开一天
The dealer loaned it to me for a 24-hour test drive.
但我们搬婴儿床时  把车后备厢撞得挺狠的
Though we did ding up the back pretty good with the crib,
所以你很可能得买下这辆面包车
so you might have bought a minivan.
我不想开这车  太老妈子风了
I don't want to drive that. It's such a mom car.
卖车那人说  这车不再只适用于妈妈
The guy at the dealership said they're not just for moms anymore.
但我还想说  那人的确认为你是我老公
Then again, he did think you were my husband.
照B超的人也这么想  卖车的人会这么想也不出奇
They thought it at the ultrasound. Why not at the car dealership?
从来没坐过在桌子的这一端
Never been on this side of the table before.
感觉可以呼风唤雨啊
I feel powerful.
是咩
Really?
有种像为了队伍筹款买新制服  而卖糖果的感觉
I feel like I'm selling candy so our team can get new uniforms.
签一张黑白照4块7毛5
Okay, so it's $4.75 for a signed black-and-white
彩照9块9毛5
and $9.95 for a color.
好的  干嘛不直接收5块和10块
Right. Why not five and ten bucks?
我带了换零钱机[性感本钱]  让人家甩甩嘛
Well, I brought my moneymaker. Let me shake it.
那个家伙正往这边看呢
Hey, that guy's looking over here.
你觉得他会是第一位买你签名的粉丝吗
You think he's your first autograph?
不知道  淡定  他过来了  他过来了
I don't know. Be cool. He's coming. He's coming.
-我超爱你的电影  -谢谢
-I love your movie.  -Well, thanks.
绝对是我人生中看过最糟糕的东西之一
It has got to be one of the worst things I've ever seen in my life.
你的爱使我困惑
Your love confuses me.
-想来张签名照吗  -好啊
- Would you like an autograph? - Sure.
-好的  签给谁  -丹尼尔
- Okay. Who do I make it out to? - Daniel.
-好的  -我想知道
- Okay. - I have to ask.
你是故意演这么烂  还是你本身演技就烂
Were you trying to be that bad,or are you just a terrible actress?
您这话更让我摸不着头脑了
That did not clear things up.
一张4块7毛5
That'll be $4.75.
-不用找了  -可我...
-Keep the change.  -But I...
全程糟透了
Nothing about that was good.
没什么好怕的  谢尔顿
There's nothing to be afraid of, Sheldon.
木塞的平均速度是每小时40公里
The average cork speed is 25 miles per hour.
如果这速度在学校操场算飞快  那么在厨房也肯定是
If that is too fast around a school,it is certainly too fast around a kitchen.
我想说  已经耗15分钟了
Been 15 minutes. Just sayin'.
好吧  我能行  再给我点时间
Okay. I can do this. Just give me a moment...
含羞草香槟来了
Mimosas coming up.
我有一次把橙汁放在冰箱的时间久到  它喝起来像含羞草酒
I once left orange juice in my fridge so long, it tasted like a mimosa.
到底放了多久
How old was it?
不好说
It's hard to say.
我喝完之后就不省人事了
I don't remember much after I drank it.
-你想来一杯吗  佩特雷斯库太太  -当然
-Would you like one, Mrs. Petrescu?  -Yes.
酒好  好友  尽在苹果蜂餐厅
Drink is fun and good friends-- Applebee's.
美国知名连锁西式平价餐厅
她的英语都是看电视学的
She's learning English from TV.
电视  很棒啊  画面回到现场主播
TV, good. Now back to you.
-大伙们  -斯图尔特
-Hey, guys.  -Hi, Stuart.
-这花是送给你的  -好漂亮的花啊  谢谢你
-These are for you.  -Oh, they're pretty. Thank you.
斯图尔特  这位是加州理工地质实验室的伯特
Stuart, this is Bert from the Caltech geology lab,
这位是楼下的佩特雷斯库太太
and this is Mrs. Petrescu from downstairs.
-很高兴认识你们  -你好
-Nice to meet you.  - Hello.
-你好  -我有错过什么吗
-Hey.  -So, what did I miss?
我们见证了谢尔顿耗费15分钟打开一瓶酒
Eh, we watched Sheldon try to open a bottle for 15 minutes.
15分钟可以帮您节省15%以上的汽车保险哦
15 minutes can save you 15% or more on car insurance.
美国政府雇员保险公司的电视广告台词
这聚会还有其他人来吗
Anybody else coming to this thing?
-你叫什么名字  -杰夫
-What's your name?  - Jeff.
好的  我最喜欢的部分就是你洗澡那一段
Okay. My favorite part is your shower scene.
这话今天我可听了不少次
Been hearing that a lot today.
我还用手机截了图
I even have a screen grab on my phone.
没错  就是这对宝贝
Yep, there they are.
-行了  快闪吧你  -给你
-Okay, let's keep it moving.  -Here you go.
我真该揍这个小子
Should've punched that guy.
想揍就揍吧  他就在那儿呢
Well, go ahead. He's right over there.
施主何苦要点破  就不能让我意淫一下吗
Why do you do that? Can't you let me have my moment?
-你好  -你好  我喜欢你拍的电影
- Hello. - Hi. I like your movies.
-谢谢  -两个我都看过哦
- Thank you! - I saw both of them.
我想你是指我的两部电影吧  但根据今日对话  "两个"还真不一定
I assume we're still talking about the movies,but after today, who knows.
-可以和你合影留念吗  -当然
-You think I could get a picture of us?  -Oh, sure.
可以和你接吻留念吗
And, uh, could you be giving me a kiss?
不行  她不能亲... 你们都有什么毛病啊
No. She cannot kiss...What is wrong with you people?!
-莱纳德  -不行  这样是不对的
- Leonard... - No, no, no. It's not okay.
-你是哪根葱啊  -我是她老公
- Who are you? - I'm her husband.
谁信啊
No, you're not.
-我真的是  -对  他真是我老公
-I am.  -Yeah, he really is.
鬼才信
No.
这车配置了倒车摄像头  光盘播放器
It's got a rearview camera, there's a DVD player--
你再看这个
oh, and check this out.
是不是感觉自己进入了未来世界
It's like we're living in the future!
给她演示后备箱  给她演示后备箱
Hey, show her the trunk! Show her the trunk!
想象一下
Imagine this:
你左手抱着娃
you've got the baby in one hand,
右手提着菜  你对自己说
groceries in the other, and you're thinking,
"我要怎么开后备箱呢"
"How am I gonna open this trunk?"
我应该会对自己说  "我那个猪头老公呢 他为什么不过来帮我"
I'm probably thinking, "Where's my husband,and why isn't he helping me?"
当轻轻一踢就可以打开后备箱时  你就根本不需要我帮忙了
You don't need my help when you can open the trunk with a simple kick of the foot.
不  人家是轻踢  你没做到位
No, it's a gentle kick; you're doing it wrong.
来  把东西都给我
Here. Give me those.
是不是应该用脚画个圈呀
Uh, maybe it was more of a circle?
卖车的人以为你们俩是夫妻  完全不"出奇"啊
It's weird that guy thought you were a couple.
-开了  -开了
- Yes! - Yes!
看到没  轻而易举
See? Easy.
看看这宽敞的后备箱空间
And look at all this cargo space.
等我们把婴儿床搬出来  你就可以上车试开了
You know, we'll get the crib out and you can take it for a test-drive.
告诉你  这辆厢型车绝对是...
I'm telling you, this van is gonna be...
伤到你的背了吗
Oh, is it your back?
是的
Uh... yeah.
没事  我们先上车
Anyway, let's just get in and see if the
试试看导航能否带我们去最近的急诊室
GPS can take us to the nearest emergency room.
所以直到艾米的公寓修好之前  她和我都将在这住
So until Amy's apartment is fixed,she and I are living here together.
我也曾和我的前女友住在一起
I lived with my old girlfriend.
她也是位地质学家
She was a geologist, too.
后来你俩吹了吗
Things didn't work out?
有一天我下班回家  她把一切都卷跑了
I came home from work one day and she had taken everything.
友情提示
I'm warning you,
记得把好的石头标本都藏起来
hide your good rocks.
我妹夫也把她的东西卷跑了
My sister's husband took all her things, too.
11点即将播出
Story at 11:00.
真的没有其他客人来了吗
Really, no one else is coming?
没有了  你们这算是练习赛
Oh, this is it. You are the practice round.
练习赛  练习什么
Practice round? For-for what?
不  他的意思是  你们是我们首先想到的人
Uh, no. He-he just means that you were the first people we thought of.
没有错
You know, exactly.
我们从未邀请过别人来吃早午餐  我想先试试水
We've never thrown a brunch before, and I wanted to work out all the kinks.
所以我就相当于你真正的朋友来之前的小白鼠
So, I'm like a lab rat before your real friends come over?
你的话非常合理  但你的表情非常生气
You see, your words sound reasonable,but your face looks angry.
快帮我一下  我最不擅长这个了
Help me out here. This is not where I shine.
斯图尔特  你知道你是我们最爱的朋友之一
Stuart, you know you're one of our favorite people.
你的表情非常真挚  但你的话却错得离谱
Okay, now, see, you look sincere,but your words are completely false.
幸好我们举行了这个练习赛  早午餐可真是不好办啊
I'm glad we did this test run. These brunches are wild!
你是怎样成功让她同意跟你约会的啊
But how did you get her to go out with you?
她刚好搬到了我家对面
Well, she moved in across the hall.
他不断纠缠让我慢慢放弃抵抗
And he started to slowly wear me down.
只要功夫深  铁杵也能磨成针
Like a river carves a canyon.
不同的是  磨针的人老是跟我显摆他的宠物精灵卡
Yeah, except the river kept showing me his Pokemon cards.
可以走了吗
Ready to go?
等等  这个人跟我说了  他怎么让《杀人恶猿》女主嫁给他
Hang on. This guy's telling me how he got the Serial Ape-ist girl to marry him.
这货吗
This guy?
可他别了个换零钱机
But he's wearing a change maker.
我觉得特性感
I think it's hot.
没错
That's right.
我是她的零钱干爹
I'm her change daddy.
我当时在想什么呢
What was I thinking?
沃罗威茨家的人搬不了重物
Wolowitzes are not a lifting people!
我们付小费给搬重物的人
We tip the lifting people!
我们真要在急诊室里等几个小时吗
Do we really have to sit for hours in the emergency room?
还不是会和上次一样  给你点冰和止痛药
They're just gonna give you ice and Advil like last time.
等我以后靠轮椅生活  你就后悔去吧
You're gonna feel terrible when I'm in a wheelchair.
顺便说一下  真有轮椅  也可以轻松地装进这台获奖的商旅车的后备箱
Which, by the way, would fit easily in the back of this award-winning minivan.
行了  我们去急诊  你就别再给这车打广告了
Fine, we'll go to the E.R. Just stop selling me on the van.
你说对  它自己就是最棒的广告
You're right. It sells itself.
你也不得不承认  行驶确实平稳
You have to admit, it's a pretty smooth ride.
噪音小点就更好了
I was hoping it'd be quieter.
生孩子要有这一半疼  你就死定了
If childbirth is half this bad,you are so screwed!
-我们到了吗  -快了
- Are we there yet?! - Soon.
为什么这么久
Why is it taking so long?!
霍华德  霍华德  看屏幕
H-Howard, Howard, look at the DVD screen.
我在播《蝙蝠侠之风云突变》  你的最爱
I put on Batman: The Animated Series. Your favorite!
太疼了  没心情看卡通
I'm in too much pain to watch cartoo...
这集好看
Oh! This is a good one.
我带这孩子的时间  可比你长多了
I've been babysitting him way longer than you have.
行  我买这台蠢车还不行吗
Fine. I'll buy the stupid van.
我从来没吃过这么好吃的薄饼
This is the best blintz I've ever had.
谢谢
Oh. Thank you.
十分美味  只差一点就能挽回刚刚万分尴尬的局面呢
It almost makes up for the incredibly awkward turn things took earlier.
我说  我还是走吧
You know what, I-I think I'm just gonna go.
不  斯图尔特  别走
No, Stuart, don't.
不  我把你和谢尔顿当成我的家人
No, I-I consider you and Sheldon like my family,
可我都不确定  你们有没有把我当朋友
and I'm not even sure you think of me as a friend.
你懂那种感受吗
You have any idea how that feels?
我们非常抱歉
We're so sorry.
我总是最后一个被想起的家伙
I'm always the last one anybody thinks of.
不  不是这样的
Well, no, that's not true.
偶尔是库萨帕里
I mean, sometimes it's Koothrappali.
但我们不应该这么说  他是有色人种  怕有歧视嫌疑
But we're not supposed to say that 'cause he's a minority.
-再见  -斯图尔特  等等
-Bye.  -Stuart, wait.
我确实知道被冷落的感受
I do know what it feels like to be left out.
我也知道那种感受
I know how it feels, too.
知道了  这是我和他之间的问题  没你事
All right, this is about me and him; you're not part of it.
斯图尔特
Stuart,
也许我们太不重视你的好  这是不可接受的错误
perhaps we do take you for granted,and that is not acceptable.
但请你知道  你真的是我们这个社交团体中非常重要的一员
Please know that you truly are a valuable member of our social group.
谢谢  这样
Thank you. You know, in fact,
我想举杯祝酒
I'd like to propose a toast.
敬斯图尔特
To Stuart.
优秀男子 好朋友
A fine man,a good friend
还是一位很棒的客人
and a wonderful guest.
-说得好  -干杯
- Hear, hear. - Cheers.
《欢乐酒店》[干杯]  现场观众实况录播
Cheers. Filmed before a live studio audience.
这就是一个哮喘矮子科学家
And that is how a short asthmatic scientist
如何征服了冷血冰山美人
landed a stone cold fox.
我都不知道跟一个人求婚
I didn't know you can propose to the same person
居然能求那么多次
so many times.
第三次我是让飞机在空中写字求婚  可惜她始终没抬头看过
The third time, I did it in skywriting, but she never looked up.
-还有一次是我跟他求婚的  -对  被我拒绝了
-You know, once, I proposed to him.  -Yeah. I said no.
-为什么  -想让她多费点功夫争取本少爷啊
-Why?  -I just wanted to make her work for it.
对  小女子一会儿就"报答"你
Yeah, that's gonna cost you later.
等等  她是为了你有钱才跟你在一起吗
Hang on. Is she just with you because you're rich?
她挣得比我还多
She makes more money than I do!
什么  您是何方神圣
What?! Who are you?!
知道我还喜欢你什么吗
Do you know what else I love about you?
你的字  写得无可挑剔
Y-Your handwriting is impeccable!
-感谢你注意到啊  -真的  我说真的
-Thank you for noticing!  -No, I mean it. I mean it.
简直像被打标签机灵魂附体了
It's like you have the soul of a label maker.
知道我喜欢你什么吗
You know what I love about you? Hmm?
你出门必备曲别针
You never leave the house without a paper clip!
上天有不测之风云  两纸有左上角待夹
You never know when two pieces of paper might temporarily need fastening in the top left corner.
我还喜欢你从来不说脏话
I also love how you never use swear words.
但事实上
You know, it turns out,
骂人不吐脏字  照样杀人于无形
you can hurt people just as well without 'em.
谁有空过来帮忙把这些东西收好
Maybe I can get a little help putting some of this stuff away.
别激动
Oh, calm down.
我不是才把五杯这个"收进"肚里吗
I already put away five of these!
你看吧  轻松堵上她嘴  不用一个脏字
You see? No muss, no fuss, not a single cuss.